[
    {
        "question": "What is the difference between a unit test and an integration test? (Choose two)",
        "options": [
            "An integration test is for validation of how different parts of the application work together",
            "An integration test verifies that the application operates as expected",
            "A unit test verifies API functionality",
            "A unit test is most specific in scope and tests small bits of code"
        ],
        "answer": ["A unit test is most specific in scope and tests small bits of code", "An integration test is for validation of how different parts of the application work together"],
        "explanation": "A <strong>unit test</strong> is focused on testing individual units or components of code in isolation. These tests aim to verify the correctness of small, specific parts of the codebase, such as functions, methods, or classes. In the context of API development, unit tests are designed to validate the behavior and functionality of individual API endpoints or functions, typically by supplying input data and asserting the expected output or behavior.<br><br>On the other hand, an <strong>integration test</strong> evaluates how different parts of the application work together as a whole. Instead of testing isolated units of code, integration tests focus on testing the interactions and dependencies between various components or modules within the application. In the context of integration testing for an API, these tests may involve scenarios where multiple API endpoints interact with each other, along with any external dependencies such as databases or third-party services. The primary goal of integration testing is to ensure that the integrated components function correctly together and that the overall behavior of the application meets the expected requirements.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "What are some benefits of using asynchronous APIs? (Choose two)",
        "options": [
            "Not having to wait on a response to process data",
            "Reduced processing time", "Increased processing time",
            "Data function reuse"
        ],
        "answer": ["Not having to wait on a response to process data", "Reduced processing time"],
        "explanation": "Using asynchronous APIs allows not having to wait for a response to process data, as the application can continue with other tasks while waiting for the response. Additionally, asynchronous APIs can reduce processing time by enabling concurrent execution of tasks, thereby improving overall system performance.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the HTTP functions used for API communication? (Choose three)",
        "options": [
            "GET",
            "SOURCE",
            "PURGE",
            "PATCH",
            "PUT"
        ],
        "answer": ["GET", "PATCH", "PUT"],
        "explanation": "The HTTP functions commonly used for API communication are PUT, GET and PATCH.<br>These methods are used to...<br><br>- Create or replace resources (PUT)<br>- Retrieve data (GET)<br>- Update existing resources (PATCH)<br><br>on the server",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the main components of SOAP messages? (Choose four)",
        "options": [
            "Envelope",
            "Header",
            "Destination",
            "Body",
            "Fault",
            "Authentication",
            "Source"
        ],
        "answer": ["Envelope", "Header", "Body", "Fault"],
        "explanation": "The main components of SOAP messages include:<br><br><strong>Envelope</strong>, which defines the start and end of the SOAP message.<br><strong>Header</strong>, which contains optional attributes and information about the message.<br><strong>Body</strong>, which contains the actual data being transmitted.<br><strong>Fault</strong>, which provides information about errors that occur during the processing of the message.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "SOAP can include fault messages. Which ones are mandatory fields? (Choose two)",
        "options": [
            "faultCode",
            "faultString",
            "faultActor", 
            "detail"
        ],
        "answer": ["faultCode", "faultString"],
        "explanation": "In SOAP, fault messages are used to communicate error information. Among the fields used in fault messages, the mandatory ones are 'faultCode' and 'faultString'. These fields are required to provide essential information about the error that occurred.<br>However, 'faultActor' and 'detail' are optional fields that may provide additional context about the fault but are not mandatory.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "In HTTP, in order to make a successful GET request to the server, the client needs to include at least which of the following? (Choose two)",
        "options": [
            "URL",
            "Method",
            "Headers",
            "Body"
        ],
        "answer": ["URL", "Method"],
        "explanation": "In HTTP, to make a successful GET request to the server, the client needs to include at least the following:<br><br>1. URL: The Uniform Resource Locator (URL) specifies the location of the resource to be retrieved.<br>2. Method: The HTTP method, in this case, GET, indicates the type of request being made by the client.<br><br>Other common HTTP methods include POST, PUT, DELETE, etc. While HTTP headers and body are optional for a GET request, the URL and method are mandatory components.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "Webhooks are like which of the following (Choose Two)",
        "options": [
            "Remote Procedure Calls",
            "Callback functions",
            "State-altering functions",
            "Event-triggered notifications"
        ],
        "answer": ["Callback functions", "Event-triggered notifications"],
        "explanation": "Webhooks are similar to the following:<br>1. <strong>Callback functions:</strong> Like callback functions, webhooks enable servers to notify or trigger actions in client applications based on specific events or conditions.<br>2. <strong>Event-triggered notifications:</strong> Webhooks are commonly used to deliver event-triggered notifications from one application to another. When a certain event occurs in the source application, a webhook sends a POST request to the destination application with relevant information.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "What are some of the features of a good SDK? (Choose three)",
        "options": [
            "Is easy to use",
            "Is well documented",
            "Integrates well with other SDKs",
            "Impacts hardware resources"
        ],
        "answer": ["Is easy to use", "Is well documented", "Integrates well with other SDKs"],
        "explanation": "A good SDK should be easy to use, allowing developers to quickly understand and implement its features. It should also be well documented, providing clear and comprehensive guidance on its usage and functionalities. Additionally, a good SDK should integrate well with other SDKs and development tools, facilitating seamless interoperability and enhancing the developer experience. However, a good SDK should not negatively impact hardware resources, as it should be designed to operate efficiently without causing excessive resource consumption.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "What APIs does the Cisco Meraki platform provide to developers? (Choose tree)",
        "options": [
            "Captive Portal API",
            "Scanning API",
            "Dashboard API",
            "Infrastructure API"
        ],
        "answer": ["Captive Portal API", "Scanning API", "Dashboard API"],
        "explanation": "From a programmability perspective, the Cisco Meraki cloud platform provides developers with several APIs. Tree of these APIs are the <strong>Captive Portal API</strong>, which allows developers to extend the built-in Meraki splash page functionality by providing complete control of the content and authentication process that a user interacts with when connecting to a Meraki wireless network. It allows administrators to customize the portal, including the clients experience connecting to the network, how the web page looks and feels and authentication and billing process.<br><br><strong>Scanning API</strong> take advantage of mMeraki smart devices with wireless and BLE functionality to provide location, analystics and report on user behavior<br><br><strong>Dashboard api</strong>, provides endpoints and resources for configuration, management and monitoring automation of Meraki cloud platform, common use cases are Provisioning neworganizations, administrators, networks, devices and more. , Configuring networks at scale, Onboarding and decommissioningg of clients, Build custom dashboards and applications.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the advantages of using an SDK? (Choose two)",
        "options": [
            "Quicker integration",
            "Faster development",
            "Advanced customization",
            "Error handling"
        ],
        "answer": ["Quicker integration", "Faster development"],
        "explanation": "Using an SDK offers several advantages, including quicker integration and faster development. SDKs typically provide pre-built components, libraries, and APIs that streamline the development process and enable developers to incorporate complex functionalities into their applications with minimal effort. This accelerates the integration of various features and services, reducing development time and effort. Additionally, SDKs often come with comprehensive documentation and support, further enhancing development speed and efficiency.",
        "multiple_choice": true
    }
]
